<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rppq9">

<title>CMV: Religion is not violent or not violent, its followers are.</title>

<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rppq9/cmv_religion_is_not_violent_or_not_violent_its/ </source>

<OP author="DurianMD">
So recently I've seen a lot of posts condemning Islam as a violent religion or a sexist religion. <claim> I point out that many Christians follow the bible which has numerous examples of sexism </claim>, but in application, <claim> there are numerous branches of Christianity that are no more sexist than secular groups. </claim> <logos> For example, Congregationalists and Universaliists. </logos> 

So, <claim> my belief is that while religion can inform the views of people, it is far more likely that religion will be used to justify actions that would have been executed any way. </claim> <logos> I think that most Jewish people don't want to stone adulterers and most Muslims don't want to stone non believers. </logos>

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
  
</OP>

<reply id="cnidt3q" author="beer_demon">
<logos> The fact I don't fear an Amish flying a plane into my office tower or a Jain blowing up my bus makes me doubt that religions have no inherent features that influence people's actions. </logos>
</reply>

<reply id="cnifgly" author="DurianMD">
<claim> The Amish and the Vedic religions in general haven't been demonized to the same extent as Muslims have. </claim> <logos> I'm far morel likely in general to be killed by a Christian than a Muslim </logos> , but <claim> that doesn't mean I should fear Christians. </claim>

<logos> So, if you're measuring by fear people feel, you're more likely to find the source of that in the mainstream media than you will in religion. </logos> <logos> Look at how scared everyone got over Ebola, a non issue for most westerners. </logos>
</reply>
  
<reply id="cnig0jf" author="beer_demon">
  <claim> I am just expressing that I find current islam a religion I mistrust. </claim> <claim> I am not saying everyone should mistrust them or that I should change my behaviour in any way </claim> , but <logos> islam has some toxic components christianity no longer has </logos>.  

  &gt; <quote> far morel likely in general to be killed by a Christian than a Muslim </quote>

  <claim> This has nothing to do with the religion but by what we are surrounded by. </claim> <pathos> I probably am more likely to be killed by a muslim than a christian *because of their religion*. </pathos> Although the odds have little to do regarding trust or feelings.
</reply>

<reply id="cniq2o0" author="DurianMD">
<logos> Your surrounded by enough Christians you're still probably more likely to be killed by a Christian for religious reasons than a Muslim. </logos> It's an issue of rate, and at that point, I'd like to see stats. <claim> I'm not going to take an emotional appeal when considering whether or not a religion has dangerous components. </claim>

What particular aspects do you find toxic?
</reply>
  
<reply id="cnirz3m" author="beer_demon">
&gt; <quote> Your surrounded by enough Christians you're still probably more likely to be killed by a Christian for religious reasons than a Muslim </quote>

  <logos> That is due to statistics, not to scripture or religious property. </logos> <logos> you are more likely to be killed by a heart attack than by a christian </logos>, <claim> this doesn't say anything about christianity </claim>.  

&gt; <quote> I'm not going to take an emotional appeal when considering whether or not a religion has dangerous components. </quote>  

  Emotional? <claim> I am just looking at the outcome of people following the religion. </claim> Facts.  

  &gt; <quote> What particular aspects do you find toxic? </quote>

  <logos> The fanatism and radical actions it allows and encourages. </logos> Do you want quran quotes or something?
</reply>

</thread>
